{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Realist artists strongly believed that their art should",
      "a": "emphasize ornate and precise details",
      "b": "represent subjects in a highly stylized manner",
      "c": "portray even the negative qualities of their subjects",
      "d": "closely follow traditional academic standards",
      "e": "focus on depicting natural scenery",
      "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
      "question": "Gustave Courbet outraged audiences by depicting",
      "a": "farmers harvesting crops in a rural field",
      "b": "ordinary workers repairing a road",
      "c": "women washing laundry by a riverside",
      "d": "fishermen mending nets by the sea",
      "e": "children playing in a village square",
      "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which artistic movement arose from dissatisfaction with the rigid rules established by the Salons?",
      "a": "Impressionism",
      "b": "Neoclassicism",
      "c": "Modernism",
      "d": "Realism",
      "e": "Romanticism",
      "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why was Luncheon on the Grass controversial?",
      "a": "It depicted a nude woman among clothed men.",
      "b": "It combined religious undertones with a secular setting.",
      "c": "It featured abstract forms instead of realistic figures.",
      "d": "It mocked the frivolous lifestyles of wealthy nobles.",
      "e": "It portrayed the working class in a glamorous light.",
      "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which artist’s work inspired the name of the Impressionist movement?",
      "a": "Camille Pissarro",
      "b": "Alfred Sisley",
      "c": "Édouard Manet",
      "d": "Georges Seurat",
      "e": "Claude Monet",
      "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
      "question": "Impressionist art is, overall, characterized by?",
      "a": "unmodified colors",
      "b": "naturalistic detail",
      "c": "thickly applied paint",
      "d": "multiple-point perspective",
      "e": "analytic space",
      "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which later artistic movement did Paul Cezánne MOST strongly influence?",
      "a": "Cubism",
      "b": "Abstract Expressionism",
      "c": "Surrealism",
      "d": "Minimalism",
      "e": "Dadaism",
      "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following characteristics was a unifying feature of the Post-Impressionist movement?",
      "a": "the inspiration drawn from classical themes and motifs",
      "b": "the search for increasingly brilliant colors",
      "c": "the focus on heightened emotions and dramatic composition",
      "d": "the emphasis on precise and realistic detail",
      "e": "the effort to capture fleeting moments in time",
      "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "question": "Georges Seurat’s art can BEST be described as",
      "a": "dynamic in composition",
      "b": "vibrant in color",
      "c": "serene in atmosphere",
      "d": "subtle in tonality",
      "e": "evocative in mood",
      "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "question": "How did Vincent van Gogh use color to create the mood of Night Café?",
      "a": "He used dark blues and grays to evoke a sense of mourning.",
      "b": "He used earthy tones to suggest a sense of warmth and comfort.",
      "c": "He used intense yellows, greens, and reds to create a jarring effect.",
      "d": "He used vibrant reds, pinks, and yellows to depict energy and vitality.",
      "e": "He used soft muted colors to convey a sense of nostalgia.",
      "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
      "question": "Paul Gauguin’s search for artistic inspiration led him to travel to",
      "a": "Tahiti",
      "b": "Italy",
      "c": "Brazil",
      "d": "Greece",
      "e": "Japan",
      "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which innovation allowed Impressionists to paint outdoors more easily?",
      "a": "synthetic paintbrushes",
      "b": "quick-drying varnishes",
      "c": "folding chairs",
      "d": "chemically based paints",
      "e": "weather-resistant palettes",
      "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following artists MOST strongly incorporated Japanese influences into his art?",
      "a": "Edgar Degas",
      "b": "Pierre-Auguste Renoir",
      "c": "Mary Cassatt",
      "d": "Paul Cézanne",
      "e": "Vincent van Gogh",
      "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "The Pre-Raphaelites’ art typically featured all of the following elements EXCEPT",
      "a": "an emphasis on nature",
      "b": "influence from pre-Renaissance art",
      "c": "complex ornamentation",
      "d": "sweeping curves",
      "e": "moralistic elements",
      "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following subjects did Art Nouveau MOST often depict?",
      "a": "religious iconography",
      "b": "still life compositions",
      "c": "urban landscapes",
      "d": "leaves and flowers",
      "e": "female figures",
      "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which statement about fauvism is FALSE?",
      "a": "Its leader was Henri Matisse.",
      "b": "It drew inspiration from Van Gogh.",
      "c": "It was named after \u201cfiery colors.\u201d",
      "d": "Its color palette shocked general sensibilities about art.",
      "e": "It rejected the need to replicate real-world color.",
      "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who developed Cubism?",
      "a": "Marcel Duchamp",
      "b": "Salvador Dalí",
      "c": "Piet Mondrian",
      "d": "Ernst Ludwig Kirchner",
      "e": "Pablo Picasso",
      "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
      "question": "Cubism was largely influenced by art from",
      "a": "Oceania",
      "b": "Africa",
      "c": "Europe",
      "d": "Asia",
      "e": "the Americas",
      "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which art movement did Vasily Kandinsky lead?",
      "a": "Bauhaus",
      "b": "Die Brücke",
      "c": "Fauvism",
      "d": "De Stijl",
      "e": "Der Blaue Reiter",
      "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
      "question": "The Armory Show is BEST known for",
      "a": "introducing modern European art to the United States",
      "b": "resulting in a split between European and American modern art",
      "c": "sparking the Harlem Renaissance",
      "d": "popularizing Surrealism in the United States",
      "e": "inspiring the Dada movement",
      "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fountain is BEST known as examples of",
      "a": "Performance art",
      "b": "Bauhaus",
      "c": "Pop Art",
      "d": "Ready-mades",
      "e": "Surrealism",
      "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which features characterized the Bauhaus movement?",
      "a": "protesting societal and art norms",
      "b": "reconciling industrial design with aesthetic",
      "c": "creating completely abstract images",
      "d": "distorting figures and angles in paintings",
      "e": "using ordinary objects to create art",
      "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "question": "Jackson Pollock is BEST known for",
      "a": "painting flat fields of color.",
      "b": "sculpting with everyday objects.",
      "c": "creating photorealistic art.",
      "d": "painting everyday objects.",
      "e": "dripping art directly onto the canvas.",
      "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
      "question": "Action Paintings and Color Fields categories in",
      "a": "Abstract Expressionism",
      "b": "Surrealism",
      "c": "De Stijl",
      "d": "Minimalism",
      "e": "Expressionism",
      "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which artist is known for producing \u201ccombines?\u201d",
      "a": "Jasper Johns",
      "b": "Willem de Kooning",
      "c": "Andy Warhol",
      "d": "Robert Rauschenberg",
      "e": "Roy Lichtenstein",
      "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "question": "Andy Warhol is BEST known for his",
      "a": "Performance Art",
      "b": "Minimalism",
      "c": "Pop Art",
      "d": "ready-mades",
      "e": "Abstract Expressionism",
      "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which art movement is MOST associated with the art of Gustave Courbet?",
      "a": "Abstract Expressionism",
      "b": "Minimalism",
      "c": "Earthworks",
      "d": "Photorealism",
      "e": "Postmodernism",
      "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements about Christo is FALSE?",
      "a": "He primarily worked alone.",
      "b": "He surrounded eleven Florida islands with pink plastic.",
      "c": "His artworks often required years of work.",
      "d": "His art put emphasis on the creation process as well as the product.",
      "e": "He was known for creating Earthworks.",
      "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which art style are the Guerilla Girls an example of?",
      "a": "Postmodernism",
      "b": "Abstract Expressionism",
      "c": "Photorealism",
      "d": "Performance Art",
      "e": "Earthworks",
      "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which postmodernist architect added a finial to the AT&T Building?",
      "a": "David Smith",
      "b": "Robert Smithson",
      "c": "Dan Flavin",
      "d": "Philip Johnson",
      "e": "Frank Stella",
      "correct_answer": "d"
    }
  ]
}